Kamal Youssef

SUMMARY

Software Developer with four years of experience in coding, testing and establishing system improvements. Currently working as a Machine learning Summer Intern. Equally proficient with front end software development, basic machine learning methods, and python scripting. Dedicated to learning, evaluating and applying new technologies in order to enhance functionality and content.

EDUCATION

New Jersey Institute of Technology (NJIT)

B.S. Information Technology (Network & Information Security)

Intended grad: May 2021 Major GPA: 3.75

Relevant Coursework: System Administration (Linux), Web Applications Development, Ethical Hacking for SysAdmins, Computer System and Networks, Advanced Programing (Java)

Technical Skills: Python (4yrs), HTML/CSS (3yrs), SQL (2yrs), JavaScript (2yr), WordPress (2yr), Visual Studio/ASP.NET(1yr), ReactJS(1yr), Machine Learning(<1yr), Git, Jira, Databricks

WORK EXPERIENCE

Merck Rahway, NJ

Merck Research Labs IT Intern

June 2020 – August 2020

- Used Databricks to train and improve deep learning models to predict properties of potential molecules in Drug Discovery and Early Development
- Worked closely with the HPC (High Performance Computing) DevOps team to design a series of Deep Learning models
 using TensorFlow in Python to improve the efficiency of HPC scheduling

Johnson & Johnson Raritan, NJ

Technology Co-op

January 2019 – August 2019

- Control-M Job Ownership Improved project completion time by 70 percent by leading my team to identify ownership for 7,000 orphaned enterprise workload automation jobs using Python scripting
- Coordination of Technology Lifecycle Management Activities ensured support of legacy operating systems by coordinating OS upgrades
- Used ASP.NET framework, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, and C# to develop a dashboard showing workload automation job
 configuration details for the internal team, as well as end-users

Advanced Integrated Solutions Fairfield, NJ

IT Assistant

June 2015 - August 2016

- Provided troubleshooting, repair, configuration, and maintenance for customers with computer and Telecom problems
- Designed and produced analytical reports highlighting competitor services

PROJECTS

NJIT Coptic Society Website, Personal Project

August 2019 – Present

(Coptic Society - Student lead Christian organization on campus)

• Increased outreach by 40 percent by using HTML/CSS to build a website for the NJIT Coptic Society, providing members a discussion board to communicate, an online retail shop for apparel, and a calendar with upcoming club events

ACTIVITIES / LEADERSHIP

Coptic Society NJIT Newark, NJ Vice President and IT Coordinator

March 2018 - Present

- Pilot board meetings, set semester goals, disseminate action items and follow up on task completion
- Coordinate Club events such as Habitat for Humanity, visiting hospitals, and various on and off-campus events
- Increased club awareness and participation by 40 percent with the implementation of the new website

St. Mark's Church Jersey City, NJ

July 2015 - Present

Youth Leader

- Organize Sunday curriculum for each subject throughout the year
- Create weekly lesson plans and educate children in weekly religious lessons every Saturday and Sunday
- Schedule and organize field trips on a monthly basis

HONORS/AWARDS

NJIT Faculty Scholarship

• Selected among 1000K+ applicants for 4-year academic achievement scholarship

September 2017 - Present